<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Witold&#39;s Work Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Witold&#39;s Work Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hockey Stick Inflection Point - China&#39;s Ageing Demographics</title>
      <link>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_1/</guid>
      <description>The Hockey Stick Inflection Point - China&amp;rsquo;s Ageing Demographics #    Demographics. When discussing China, it’s the elephant in the room that few are really talking about. We get it. It’s a slow undercurrent. And human attention tends to dart towards the topics that move fast. But it’s arguably the single biggest factor that’s going to cut across industries and define China’s story for the next 20-30 years. Just to illustrate, how are property prices going to behave as there are simply fewer young people to take out those mortgages (here&amp;rsquo;s our take in this post)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is China Pursuing &#34;Common Prosperity&#34;?</title>
      <link>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_2/</guid>
      <description>Why is China Pursuing &amp;ldquo;Common Prosperity?&amp;quot; #    Contents #    Income percentiles
  Wealth percentiles
  Private &amp;amp; public wealth ratios
  House affordability ratios
  Global Gini coefficient
  Poverty lines over time
  China urban-rural divide
    The Setup #  China’s leadership is advancing “Common Prosperity” as an overarching policy objective. Throughout history the Chinese state has advocated stability as a core value (interesting but dense read here: “1587, a Year of No Significance”).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Changed in China&#39;s Marriage Patterns?</title>
      <link>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_3/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s Changed in China&amp;rsquo;s Marriage Patterns? #    Contents #    Hypergamy: What Is It?
  The Reversal of a Trend
  So What?
    The Setup #  China has experienced unprecedented economic growth since its reforms in the 1980s. But how has this impacted its marriage patterns?
 1. Hypergamy: What Is It? #  Hypergamy is a fancy word for the tendency in humans for men to mate across and down the socio-economic hierarchy, whereas women mate across and up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The History of Chinese VC in One Chart</title>
      <link>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://witolot.github.io/docs/birds_eye_view/birds_eye_4/</guid>
      <description>The History of Chinese VC in One Chart #     China VC in one chart. Count of A-rounds per year on Y-axis. Segmented by sector. A-rounds only (A, A+, excludes preA) because in our interpretation that’s really the type of round that signifies whether or not a sector is taking off. Anything prior to a proper A-round (angel, seed, preA) is still quite speculative. Anything after (&amp;gt;=B rounds) is usually further validation of a particular company but in quantitative terms these get fewer in the aggregate and do not really capture whether the sector is getting wind in their sails, which is what we’re after.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
